[
    {
        "question": "Who invented Java Programming?",
        "options": [
            "Guido van Rossum",
            "James Gosling",
            "Dennis Ritchie",
            "Bjarne Stroustrup"
        ],
        "answer": "James Gosling",
        "category": "6568307e5ef4f6013922e379"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is true about Java?",
        "options": [
            "Java is a sequence-dependent programming language",
            "Java is a code dependent programming language",
            "Java is a platform-dependent programming language",
            "Java is a platform-independent programming language"
        ],
        "answer": "Java is a platform-independent programming language",
        "category": "6568307e5ef4f6013922e379"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which component is used to compile, debug and execute the java programs?",
        "options": [
            "JRE",
            "JIT",
            "JDK",
            "JVM"
        ],
        "answer": "JDK",
        "category": "6568307e5ef4f6013922e379"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following is not a Java feature?",
        "options": [
            "Object-oriented",
            "Use of pointers",
            "Portable",
            "Dynamic and Extensible"
        ],
        "answer": "Use of pointers",
        "category": "6568307e5ef4f6013922e379"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these cannot be used for a variable name in Java?",
        "options": [
            "identifier & keyword",
            "identifier",
            "keyword",
            "none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "answer": "keyword",
        "category": "6568307e5ef4f6013922e379"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the extension of java code files?",
        "options": [
            ".js",
            ".txt",
            ".class",
            ".java"
        ],
        "answer": ".java",
        "category": "6568307e5ef4f6013922e379"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not an OOPS concept in Java?",
        "options": [
            "Polymorphism",
            "Inheritance",
            "Compilation",
            "Encapsulation"
        ],
        "answer": "Compilation",
        "category": "6568307e5ef4f6013922e379"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is not the use of “this” keyword in Java?",
        "options": [
            "Referring to the instance variable when a local variable has the same name",
            "Passing itself to the method of the same class",
            "Passing itself to another method",
            "Calling another constructor in constructor chaining"
        ],
        "answer": "Passing itself to the method of the same class",
        "category": "6568307e5ef4f6013922e379"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Truncation in Java?",
        "options": [
            "Floating-point value assigned to a Floating type",
            "Floating-point value assigned to an integer type",
            "Integer value assigned to floating type",
            "Integer value assigned to floating type"
        ],
        "answer": "Floating-point value assigned to an integer type",
        "category": "6568307e5ef4f6013922e379"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a type of polymorphism in Java Programming?",
        "options": [
            "Multiple polymorphism",
            "Compile time polymorphism",
            "Multilevel polymorphism",
            "Execution time polymorphism"
        ],
        "answer": "Compile time polymorphism",
        "category": "6568307e5ef4f6013922e379"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the extension of compiled java classes?",
        "options": [
            ".txt",
            ".js",
            ".class",
            ".java"
        ],
        "answer": ".class",
        "category": "6568307e5ef4f6013922e379"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which exception is thrown when java is out of memory?",
        "options": [
            "MemoryError",
            "OutOfMemoryError",
            "MemoryOutOfBoundsException",
            "MemoryFullException"
        ],
        "answer": "OutOfMemoryError",
        "category": "6568307e5ef4f6013922e379"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these are selection statements in Java?",
        "options": [
            "break",
            "continue",
            "for()",
            "if()"
        ],
        "answer": "if()",
        "category": "6568307e5ef4f6013922e379"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these keywords is used to define interfaces in Java?",
        "options": [
            "intf",
            "Intf",
            "interface",
            "Interface"
        ],
        "answer": "interface",
        "category": "6568307e5ef4f6013922e379"
    }
]